Contact

8128038001 (Mobile) yash120394@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yash120394 (LinkedIn) github.com/yash120394 (Personal)

Top Skills

Team Leadership
Team Management
Microsoft Office

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
Sanskrit (Elementary)

Certifications

Machine Learning

Yash Kumar

Actively looking for full-time Data Scientist, Data Analyst role | Ex Snapchat Analyst Intern | Graduate Research Assistant at Indiana University

Bloomington

Summary

Data enthusiast with hands on experience in Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Visualization and Computer Vision. Graduate student at Indiana University with professional experience in Data Science for 2.5 years. Motivated to grow as an individual and learn new things.

Experience

Indiana University Bloomington 6 months

Associate Instructor August 2020 - Present (1 month) Bloomington, Indiana, United States

Graduate Research Assistant March 2020 - Present (6 months)

Bloomington, Indiana, United States

- Assisted professor for carrying out different methodologies to map functional tissue units in human body using Computer Vision and Deep Learning technologies
- Incorporated various Deep Convolutional networks like Faster RCNN,
 Mask RCNN and AlexNet to detect tissues on different stained tissue blocks;
 Compared the performance of each model on different accuracy metrics like F-score, Precision, Recall and IoU

Snap Inc.

Strategy Analyst Intern

May 2020 - August 2020 (4 months)

Los Angeles, California, United States

 Streamlined the process of using weekly advertisement sales data for generating financial reports; Increased the efficiency of historical pipeline analysis by 40%

- Automated the process of linking recurring reports with BigQuery using Google API; Incorporated validation checks on parsed data to check consistency
- Prepared weekly advertiser pacing reports for comparing actuals vs forecasts

TransOrg Analytics

2 years 2 months

Analytics Specialist

March 2019 - July 2019 (5 months)

Gurgaon, Haryana, India

- Devised a probabilistic model using Gradient Boosting Classifier to predict propensity of customers to buy personal loans which optimized marketing cost by 30% with a coverage of 64% of total customer base
- Collaborated with a leading FMCG client for voice-based ordering system in the sales rep application; Extracted keywords like product name, quantity and measurement from Google speech API's output using nltk

Data Analyst

June 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 9 months)

Gurgaon, India

- Created time series model using different models like Prophet, ARIMA and STL modelling to forecast different network's parameters and compare actuals vs forecast
- Segmented source IP addresses on network's various parameters like bytes, packets, session time, denied flows, etc. using K-Means Clustering to flag anomalous traffic
- Developed a multi-class classification model using Random Forest to predict potential cross-sell customers which achieved 74% of target cross-sell customers in 34% of the total customer base

Indian Institute of Science (IISc)

Project Intern

June 2016 - July 2016 (2 months)

Designed mechanism for probing micron movement level resolution for Electrolithography Machine | Devised new ideas for making Smart Urinals which can be installed in public toilets

UrbanClap

Business Development

December 2015 - January 2016 (2 months)

In the Inbound team, pitched multiple deals to the service providers, converting 120+ service providers Received Letter of Recommendation from Abhiraj Bahl (Founder of UC) for acquiring 200% of the targets

FCA Fiat Chrysler Automobiles Summer Trainee June 2015 - July 2015 (2 months)

Responsible for examining the Quality and analysing MTM-UAS Time study of various delibra in Body Shop, Car Division thereby increasing efficiency of workers by 25%

Education

Indiana University Bloomington

Master's degree, Computational Science · (2019 - 2021)

Netaji Subhas Institute of Technology
Bachelor of Engineering, Mechatronics, Robotics, and Automation
Engineering · (2013 - 2017)

Mount Carmel School
Science with Maths · (2010 - 2012)